#### ADVISORY SOFTWARE ENGINEER

#### Summary

Senior Lead Release Engineer specializing in Continuous Integration and Deployment. Experienced with several IBM and Open Source grown tools, build and packaging software and automation techniques. Extensive work experience with Open Source Software projects as well as Enterprise Level Software projects. Strong background in project planning and leading agile based team projects. Highlights

- Jenkins CI/CD Server Management
- Rational Build Forge Server
- Maven Builds
- Sonatype Nexus Server Management
- IBM Appscan
- Docker

- CI/CD Pipeline automation
- Rational Team Concert management
- Git/GHE
- Tivoli Storage Manager
- Tivoli FastBack
- Linux Build Environments

## Accomplishments

- Lead build team to convert process from Waterfall Methodology to Agile Methodology. Converting builds from 8 hour process to multiple components builds that build in 10 mins (reducing total time to about 15 mins).
- Lead team to migrate source code from local Git server to a GitHub Enterprise Environment.
- Lead and coached development team on Maven based software development practices and how to adjust to automate the software
  pipeline to achieve Continuous Integration and Deployment strategies to significantly improve time between developer code check in, unit
  testing, integration testing, deployment, and functional testing.

## Experience

08/2015 to Current

Advisory Software Engineer Horizon Software International, Llc i1/4 Ithaca, NY

- I was promoted to lead the efforts to create a brand-new build process and significantly improve on previous build process. In this role, I
  mentored team of engineers on the best practices for agile software development and continuous integration. We were working on a brandnew project from scratch and wanted to make sure the development process was stream lined to produce shorter development to product
  testing times, helping us keep pace with the Open Source communities.
- The skills and lessons learned from working on the new offerings were applied to stream line existing offerings, with the goal to be enable our developers to rapidly make changes and deliver patches to customers.
- The role expanded to develop cloud based solutions as well as our primary on-prem solution. Our goal was to increase the avenues we could use to expose customers to our products.

## 10/2012 to 08/2015

Build Software Engineer/Devops Engineer Sumaria Systems, Inc. il/4 Poway, CA

- Experience with the following Software Solutions: Build Management Systems: Jenkins, Build Forge Source Code Management: Rational Team Concert (RTC), Git Archive and Backup Solutions: Tivoli Storage Manager, Tivoli FastBack Build Tools: Maven, IBM AppScan, Sonar Nexus, Common Component Build (CCB), Chef Part of a build and integration organization that serviced multiple development groups.
- Lead the Build and Automation group that serviced IBM's BigData BigInisghts solution.
- Directly responsible for helping 250+ developers from three different sites: US, China, and India.
- Primary role was to manage build process, create automation, and lead education on software delivery to the developers.
- Examples of tasks include: Creating and managing Jenkins Master, setup and install Jenkins Slaves (build machines), automate build and release process, help developers setup Maven pom.xml files, manage file servers, create installable images of the product and send them to QA teams, create new source code streams and branches and manage parallel development activities, among other build related tasks.
- For the past year, our primary mission has shifted to automate our Continuous Integration and Continuous Deployment strategies.

# 08/2008 to 09/2012

Staff Software Support Engineer International Business Machines IBM i1/4 City, STATE

- Worked on enterprise level support team for IBM's Tivoli Storage Manager software suite and IBM's Tivoli FastBack Software solution.
- Was the lead Support Engineer for the Level 2 support team on the FastBack software solution.
- On Tivoli Storage Manager was a specialist on the Level 2 Tivoli Data Protection (TDP) team
- The FastBack software solution performed block level backups on Windows servers.
- Software was designed to help small to mid level companies manage their backup and restore activities for mission critical systems, perform Bare Metal Restores, provide instant restore capabilities, among other functions.
- The IBM Tivoli Storage Manager TDP team specialized in working with API's to third party software such as Microsoft Exchange Server, Microsoft SQL Server, Oracle databases, Lotus Notes servers, among others.
- Example of tasks on the Level 2 support teams include: working directly with IBM customers to setup and configure software in their
  environment, helping customers with mission critical restore scenarios, debugging complex configuration errors, working with development
  group to help identify code bugs and provide patches to customers, creating online documentation to for customer use, among other related
  tasks.

#### 07/2004 to 07/2005

Research and Development Intern summer intern General Dynamics, Advanced Information Systems il/4 City, STATE

- The first summer I researched software solutions that would help the developers manage their project's files and documentation.
- Setup and demoed a Microsoft SharePoint server to the research group.
- Second Summer I worked on a modified Trace Route program on Windows platform that would track additional details about each hop
  from on IP to another IP address.

## 09/2001 to 04/2003

Information Technologist Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Company il/4 City, STATE

- As an Intern I worked in TSMC's IT help desk center.
- My responsibilities included answering calls, creating tickets into call center database, assisting with large scale updates, such as upgrades to
  hardware and software for employee's workstations, problem solving connectivity or network issues for employees, problem solving printer
  malfunctions, setup and configuration of new employee workstations, installing new software onto workstations, debugging client side email
  issues, among other related tasks.

### Education

Bachelors of Science: Computer Engineering San Jose State University Computer Engineering

AA: Mathematics West Valley College Mathematics

AS: Applied Physics West Valley College Applied Physics

Associates of Liberal Arts West Valley College Received Dean's Honor List Award for each Strong communication skills developed working with external and internal customers.

Overall Qualifications Technical Qualifications

Skills

Agile, API, automate, Automation, Backup, call center, Strong communication skills, hardware, client, databases, database, debugging, delivery, documentation, email, Engineer, xml, file servers, help desk, IBM, IP, Lotus Notes, managing, Microsoft Exchange Server, Microsoft SharePoint, Windows, Windows platform, enterprise, network, Oracle, printer, problem solving, QA, research, servers, Software Engineering, Software Engineer, Microsoft SQL Server, Tivoli, troubleshooting, upgrades